thewalkingcompany.com 2003-08-06

# Privacy Policy

  | 

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for TheWalkingCo.com. 

Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, this privacy statement will notify you of:

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personal identification is collected from you through the website.
  2. Who is collecting the information.
  3. How the information is used.
  4. With whom the information may be shared.
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control.
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you feel that we are not abiding by our posted privacy policy, you should contact TheWalkingCo.com Customer Service via email at [service@TheWalkingCo.com](mailto:service@TheWalkingCo.com) or by telephone at 1-888-233-6743.

**Information Collection and Use**   
The TheWalkingCo.com website is operated by TheWalkingCo.com, Inc. which is owned by Brown Shoe Company and The Walking Company. TheWalkingCo.com, Inc., The Walking Company, Inc., and Brown Shoe Company, Inc. are the sole owners of all information collected on this site. This information will not be shared with, sold or rented to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. This information is collected from users at several different points on the TheWalkingCo.com website. 

**Preferred Customers**   
In order to become a Preferred Customer, you must first complete the registration form. During registration you are required to give personal contact information (such as name and email address). This information is used to reward loyal customers for their business. By becoming a Preferred Customer, you are able to take advantage of special offers we make available to Preferred Customers about new promotions, fashion trends, etc. It is also more convenient for a Preferred Club Customer to make purchases online.

**Orders**   
We request information from you on our order form. Here you must provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customers' orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with you. 

**Cookies**   
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the hard drive of your computer, containing information about you. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once you close your browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by accepting a cookie from our site, you will not have to log in your password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If you reject the cookie, you may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that you will be limited in some areas of our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our customers to enhance the experience on our site. 

**Log Files**   
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track users' movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

**Sharing**   
The personal information you have provided us and information about your order will never be shared with third parties. This information may, however, be combined with other information (such as demographic information and past purchase information) and used to make our future marketing efforts more efficient. 

**Links**   
From time to time, TheWalkingCo.com may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this site. 

**Surveys and Contests**   
From time to time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

**Security**   
TheWalkingCo.com takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration form or order form asks you to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just "surfing."

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Furthermore, all employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Our employees are regularly notified and reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers' information is protected. Finally, the servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. 

If you have questions about the security of our website, email us at [service@TheWalkingCo.com](mailto:service@TheWalkingCo.com)

**Special Offers**   
Established Preferred Customers will occasionally receive information on products, services, and special promotions. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see "Choice and Opt-Out" below. 

**Site and Service Updates**   
We also send our users site and service announcement updates. We may communicate with you to provide requested services and, in regards to issues relating to your account, via email or phone. 

**Correcting or Updating Personal Information**   
If your personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if you no longer desire our service, we will endeavor to provide a way for you to correct, update or remove your personal data provided to us. This can usually be done at the Preferred Customer Account maintenance page or by emailing us at [service@TheWalkingCo.com](mailto:service@TheWalkingCo.com)

**Choice and Opt-out**   
Our users are given the opportunity to "opt-out" of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information. For example, our Preferred Customer Account information form has an 'opt-out' mechanism so users who register with us, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists. If you no longer wish to receive our promotional materials you may opt-out of receiving these communications by either visiting our [TWC Member Account](https://www.thewalkingco.com/services/customer/editemailpassword.asp) information page or by sending us an email at [service@TheWalkingCo.com](mailto:service@TheWalkingCo.com). 

**Notification of Changes**   
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by way of an email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we may use your information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
